SHANNON HOLLOWAY

shannonholloway.com

info@shannonholloway.com

SUMMARY

Researcher and designer with 8+ years of experience realizing new initiatives in industry, academia, and government. Lead interdisciplinary teams to develop high-impact research strategies, translate research findings into actionable insights, design human-centered solutions, and promote knowledge sharing.

EXPERIENCE

Research Lead | NYU Ability Project

May 2017 - Present Brooklyn, NY

Lead interdisciplinary team in conducting user research, rapid prototyping and testing with individuals with disabilities to inform universal design in home entertainment. Partner with Charter Spectrum and NYC Media Lab to deliver white paper on accessibility and experimental prototypes of conversational interfaces.

Research Assistant | NYU Tandon School of Engineering

Sep. 2016 - May 2017 Brooklyn, NY

Conducted stakeholder interviews and observations of user behavior in a university innovation space. Partnered with MakerSpace management to design, test and iterate on spatial and organizational design solutions to foster a collaborative STEM learning environment.

Researcher + Service Designer | NYC Mayor's Office of Operations May - Aug. 2016 Brooklyn, NY

Conducted field research for a new broadband Internet service in public housing. Developed operational framework and templates for pilot Service Design Lab to scale service design across City agencies.

UX Lead | Pearson

Dec. 2014 - Apr. 2015 New York, NY

Oversaw transition of product design from agency to in-house for the Pearson System of Courses K1 and 2–12 apps for iOS and Win8 tablets. Managed team of 7 designers split across 10 scrum teams.

UX Designer | Bluefly

Jun. 2014 - Oct. 2014 New York, NY

Lead stakeholder workshops to define requirements, UX strategy, and information architecture for platform migration of e-commerce website featuring over 35,000 products.

UX Designer + Strategist | CredSpark

Jun. 2013 - July 2014 Brooklyn, NY

Partnered with stakeholders to discover customer needs and define UX strategy for product ramp up from MVP to 1.0.

Executive Assistant | Steadfast Financial LP

Oct. 2011 - Feb. 2014 New York, NY

Conducted proprietary research, optimized deal flow and operations for a new venture capital arm of a \$5B hedge fund.

EDUCATION

NYU Tandon School of Engineering

M.S. Integrated Digital Media Brooklyn, NY GPA 3.85 May 2017

Thesis on Human-Centered Design of Mixed Reality Environments

Coursework in Human Factors, Ergonomics, Research Methods

University of California at Berkeley

B.A. Practice of Art Berkeley, CA GPA 3.71 May 2009

SKILLS

Stakeholder Workshops Interviews and Ethnography Surveys and Analytics **Usability Testing** Heuristic Evaluation **Experimental Research Methods** Competitive Analysis Customer Journey Mapping Presentations and Storytelling Service and Organization Design UX and Interaction Design Design Strategy Web Accessibility Rapid Prototyping Information Architecture Voice and Gesture Interfaces Best Practices and Standards Agile UX Process Planning and Roadmapping Operations Management Cross-Functional Teamwork Spanish Proficiency